Hello, I'm Peter.
大家好 我是Peter
And I'm experimenting with creating music in
我正在尝试在web浏览器中
the web browser. 4-p
创作音乐 4-p
And what I want to show you here is a web application
我想在这里向各位展示的是一个
for creating music in the web browser.
在web浏览器中创作音乐的web应用
This video here is also being recorded
本视频也是
in that same application.
在同一个应用中录制的
It's a camera view here on the bottom right.
右下角是一个镜头视角
And on the left side, here
左侧这一部分
it is code
是生成音乐的代码 12-p
This is actually a live coding studio,
这实际上是一个在线编程工作室
where you have the notes to be played here
在注释里写下要播放的音符
in comments, and you have the durations
还有持续时间
and the velocities.
和速度
And on the right side here
右边的代码
is a language called assembly script,
是用一种叫做AssemblyScript的语言
which compiles to WebAssembly. 19-p
它可以编译成WebAssembly 19-p
And what I have here is the instruments.
下面这些就是乐器
There are actually no recorded instruments here.
这里实际上没有预先录制的乐器
It's just generated in real time and you have all the math
它是实时生成的 通过所有的运算
and all the code here for generating the sound. 23-p
和所有的代码来生成声音 23-p
When I actually
当我在
(playing note on keyboard)
（在键盘上演奏音符）
play here on my MIDI keyboard.
在我的MIDI键盘上演奏时
(playing keyboard)
（弹奏键盘）
The code here on the right side is running and calculating
右边的代码正在运行
all the samples for the instruments in real time.
并且实时计算乐器的所有样本
(playing the keyboard) 30-p
（弹奏键盘） 30-p
I have a string
我这里有很多乐器 比如弦乐
(string instrument notes playing)
（弦乐乐器音符演奏）
which you can actually see the code for down here.
你可以在下面看到它的代码
I'm not going to go into the code right now.
我暂且不深入讲解这些代码
That has to be another session.
等到下次研讨会再说
(playing the keyboard) 36-p
（弹奏键盘） 36-p
You can create lots of interesting instruments here.
你可以在这里创造出很多有趣的乐器
(flute instrument notes playing)
（长笛乐器音符演奏）
That's the flute and also have a drum here.
这是笛乐 我这里还有鼓乐
(drum beat playing) 40-p
（鼓点演奏） 40-p
And actually I have this leading beat that is recorded here
我其实在这里录了一小段节拍
so I can start playing it.
我可以直接演奏出来
(musical beat playing) 43-p
（音乐节拍演奏） 43-p
Why not record something while I'm at it?
不如趁这个时候录点音乐吧？
(playing bass notes over musical beat) 45-p
（用贝斯音符搭配音乐节拍） 45-p
And what you just saw there was that after I recorded,
你刚才看到的是 我录完的这段音乐
it actually inserted the code here
实际上变成了这些代码
on the left side here.
插入到了左侧栏
You got all the notes I played
有我演奏的所有音符
and they did the durations and the velocities. 50-p
还有持续时间和速度 50-p
This is a full environment for creating music.
这是一套创作音乐的完整环境
You have recording and creating the instruments you got all you
你可以录音 创造乐器
need here actually for creating a complete piece of music. 53-p
创作完整音乐作品所需的东西都在这里 53-p
But the very important thing for making this a pleasant
但是对于音乐家和键盘手来说
experience to work with for a musician and a keyboard player
要想营造愉快的创作体验
(playing the keyboard)
（弹奏键盘）
is that you actually get instant response
非常重要的一点是在弹奏时
from the MIDI keyboard when you play.
得到MIDI键盘的即时响应
And it's just a matter of milliseconds.
而这只是1毫秒的问题
If it takes like 10 milliseconds,
如果需要10毫秒才能响应
then it's too much. 61-p
那就太长了 61-p
On this Mac that I have here,
在我的这台Mac上
that's no problem. It just works as it should.
没有问题 它能够正常运作
It's just a low end MacBook air.
这是台低端的MacBook Air
It's not problem at all, but it's a challenge
完全没有问题 但这种延迟
across systems.
在别的系统上
This latency. 67-p
是个挑战 67-p
For example, if you go to a windows computer,
例如在一台Windows电脑上
you generally get good performance,
一般来说你会体验到很好的性能
but you get this lag of 10 milliseconds,
但你也会遇到10毫秒的延迟
which is really too much to have a good playing experience.
这对于良好的演奏体验来说实在太长了
It's okay for listening, but maybe also for gameplay.
你可以在这种延迟下听音乐 或者玩游戏
But actually when you are using this as a musician
但当你作为音乐人使用它时
you need that instant response. 74-p
你真的需要这种即时响应 74-p
And also you see that, for example,
而且你也可以看到 比如说
a laptop running on battery. Also, this is with Windows.
一台用电池的Windows笔记本电脑
It's not problem with the Mac.
Mac就没有这种问题
Then you actually hear that the sound is degraded.
你会听到音质被削弱了
There are clicks, there are...
夹杂一些杂声 一些…
sometimes it just stops and it's not the experience
有时候甚至会直接停止 这种体验
it should be.
不应该有
These are things that really has to be improved
这些都是真正需要改进的地方
in order to make this, because the possibilities are
因为其巨大的潜力是
very exciting here.
非常令人兴奋的
Just, this is a very simple application,
这只是一个非常简单的应用
but you could create full replacements for what we
但你可以创造完整的替代品
have in desktop apps today for creating music. 87-p
替代如今音乐创作的桌面应用程序 87-p
I really think there are some interesting possibilities
我认为把这个领域扩展到web上时
there when you expand that area onto the web. 89-p
会很有前景 89-p
And also across browsers,
另外 跨浏览器支持
for example, in Firefox,
例如Firefox
you don't have the MIDI support.
现在是不支持MIDI的
It's a very good AudioWorklet implementation.
这是一个优良的AudioWorklet实现
Audioworklet is the technology that
AudioWorklet是一种
can bin this WebAssembly code to the Web Audio API.
将WebAssembly代码与Web Audio API绑定的技术
And makes it possible to have this low latency,
它使低延迟成为可能
this instant response when you play.
让你在演奏时获得即时响应
This works very good on Firefox,
这在Firefox上效果很好
but you don't have a MIDI connectivity.
但没有任何关于MIDI的接口
You have to find other solutions for connecting
这就需要找到其他解决方案
a MIDI keyboard to Firefox. 101-p
将MIDI键盘连接到Firefox 101-p
And this is also important in order to get this fully
为了达到这种完全可用的体验
usable experience is that you have this
很重要的一点
working across browsers. 104-p
就是要支持不同的浏览器 104-p
But other than that, I think this is
但除此之外
very interesting technology.
我认为这是非常有趣的技术
I've created quite a bit of music with it so far.
到目前为止 我已经用它创作了很多音乐
I use it for all my music now, and I think it's great.
我现在创作音乐都用它 我认为它很棒
I really hope that we will see this stable and
我真的希望以后能够看到
performant and you get this low latency
在所有的浏览器或平台上
across all browsers or platforms. 111-p
实现稳定且性能良好的低延迟 111-p
That's the point I really want to make today.
我今天想说的就是这些
And I hope can get some attention in the future.
我希望在未来能引起一些关注
Thank you for watching.
感谢观看